<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Linux on MoonLab</title><link>https://moonlab.top/en/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on MoonLab</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.143.1</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 08:24:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://moonlab.top/en/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install Debian on Android devices to become a BT download server</title><link>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2024/debian-on-android/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 08:24:02 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2024/debian-on-android/</guid><description>The author discusses their experience with VNC and setting up a Debian environment on an Android device using Termux. After their Android device became unusable due to battery issues, they installed Debian with a simple script. They advise against using Ubuntu in Termux due to limitations with systemd and snap. The post also covers the Phantom Process Killer in Android 12, providing ADB commands to disable it. For VNC access, the author installs the XFCE desktop environment and configures the VNC server to allow connections beyond localhost. They also mention potential future installations like Gogs for a local Git server.</description></item><item><title>[Dual Boot] Windows Update Destroyed My Linux System</title><link>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2024/windows-update-broke-linux-system/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 08:28:35 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2024/windows-update-broke-linux-system/</guid><description>After a Windows update, the user&amp;rsquo;s Linux system failed to boot due to a 90-second wait and encountered dependency failures. Investigation revealed that Windows swapped the order of the Linux partition and the recovery partition, leading to the issue. The user resolved the problem by repairing Linux, updating fstab, reinstalling Grub, and using efibootmgr to change the boot order.</description></item></channel></rss>