<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on MoonLab</title><link>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on MoonLab</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.143.1</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 08:24:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://moonlab.top/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install Debian on Android devices to become a BT download server</title><link>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2024/debian-on-android/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 08:24:02 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2024/debian-on-android/</guid><description>The author discusses their experience with VNC and setting up a Debian environment on an Android device using Termux. After their Android device became unusable due to battery issues, they installed Debian with a simple script. They advise against using Ubuntu in Termux due to limitations with systemd and snap. The post also covers the Phantom Process Killer in Android 12, providing ADB commands to disable it. For VNC access, the author installs the XFCE desktop environment and configures the VNC server to allow connections beyond localhost. They also mention potential future installations like Gogs for a local Git server.</description></item><item><title>[Dual Boot] Windows Update Destroyed My Linux System</title><link>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2024/windows-update-broke-linux-system/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 08:28:35 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2024/windows-update-broke-linux-system/</guid><description>After a Windows update, the user&amp;rsquo;s Linux system failed to boot due to a 90-second wait and encountered dependency failures. Investigation revealed that Windows swapped the order of the Linux partition and the recovery partition, leading to the issue. The user resolved the problem by repairing Linux, updating fstab, reinstalling Grub, and using efibootmgr to change the boot order.</description></item><item><title>Git push results in permission denied error 403</title><link>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2023/git-err/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 12:09:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2023/git-err/</guid><description>When trying to use &lt;code>git push -u origin main&lt;/code>, a permission error occurred, indicating that the old user was denied access. To resolve this issue, the author attempted to reset the commit author using &lt;code>git commit --amend --reset-author&lt;/code>, but the problem persisted. Ultimately, a solution was found on Stack Overflow： deleting the old credentials successfully resolved the issue, saving an hour of time.</description></item><item><title>Android Notes 1 - Analysis of the View Event Distribution Mechanism</title><link>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2019/android-view-motionevent/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 11:07:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2019/android-view-motionevent/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="coo-coo-coo">Coo Coo Coo&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Basically, this article summarizes the chapter on the View event distribution mechanism from the book &amp;ldquo;Exploring Android Art Development.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A long time ago, Android development notes were too superficial.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="brief-introduction">Brief Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>As we all know, an event sequence starts with MotionEvent.ACTION_DOWN (press), followed by multiple MotionEvent.MOVE (move) events, and ends with a MotionEvent.ACTION_UP (release).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The order of event transmission is: Activity -&amp;gt; Window -&amp;gt; DecorView -&amp;gt; RootView (the View you set).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The question of Zhihu Daily</title><link>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2019/android-zhihu-daily/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 20:34:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://moonlab.top/en/posts/2019/android-zhihu-daily/</guid><description>The author started developing a third-party Zhihu Daily client during the summer vacation, using the MVP architecture. They encountered some issues, such as global exception handling and JSON parsing, and chose to use Picasso to load images. To solve the problem of images being too wide in the WebView, the author adjusted the image size through JavaScript. In the end, the author completed the basic loading and viewing functions and shared the code on GitHub. Despite the challenges in the development process, the author still enjoyed the experience.</description></item></channel></rss>